Frank Ormsby papers, circa 1967-2004
Emory University
- Writings by Frank Ormsby, 1970-1995, Series 3; Boxes 17-29; OP6-9, 20
  - Poetry by Frank Ormsby, 1970-1995, Subseries 3.1; Boxes 17-22
    - Collected poetry, 1970-1995, Subseries 3.1b; Box 17: folder 3 - Box 20: folder 7
      - The Bees' Nest [1980-1981], Tables of contents, MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Uncollected poetry, 1970-1995, Subseries 3.1c; Box 20: folder 8 - Box 22
      - "Action Man," TS (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - "Aerial Photograph," TS [circa pre-1971] [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Derrycullen Churchyard" for MS] (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - "After the Funeral," MS, TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - "After an Image in David Selznick's A Farewell to Arms," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - "Aimed at an Acquaintance," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - "Among the Outpatients," MS (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - "Apple-Picking Deferred," MS [variant title: "A Drunk Man Reads ‘After Apple Picking'"] (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - "At a Christening," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - "At the Funeral," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 16)
      - "At the Optician's," TS (Box 20, Folder 17)
      - "The Atlantic Wall," TS [included with A Northern Spring materials] (Box 20, Folder 18)
      - "Attic," MS (Box 20, Folder 19)
      - "The Auction Room," MS (Box 20, Folder 20)
      - "Baby Breast-Feeding," MS, TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 20, Folder 21)
      - "Baptism," TS [See Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Sensualities"]
      - "The Barn," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 22)
      - "Bats," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 23)
      - "The Beach at Rossnowlagh," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 24)
      - "Beans in a biscuit-tin," MS [See Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Store of Candles, "The Practical Farms"]
      - "A Belfast Journal," notebook (Box 20, Folder 25)
      - "A Belfast Journal I," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 26)
      - "A Belfast Journal II," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 27)
      - "A Belfast Journal III," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 28)
      - "A Belfast Journal IV," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 29)
      - "A Belfast Journal V," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 30)
      - "A Belfast Journal VI," MS (Box 20, Folder 31)
      - "A Belfast Journal VII," MS (Box 20, Folder 32)
      - "A Belfast Journal VIII," MS (Box 20, Folder 33)
      - "A Belfast Journal IX," MS (Box 20, Folder 34)
      - "A Belfast Journal X," MS (Box 20, Folder 35)
      - "A Belfast Journal XI," MS (Box 20, Folder 36)
      - "A Belfast Journal I, II, III, IV, VII, VIII," TS (Box 20, Folder 37)
      - "The Betting-Shop," TS (Box 20, Folder 38)
      - "Beware of the Dog," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 39)
      - "Bicycles in the Hall," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 20, Folder 40)
      - "Big Deals in the Avenue," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 20, Folder 41)
      - "The Black Babies," MS, TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 20, Folder 42)
      - "Bonfire Pile, Belfast," TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 20, Folder 43)
      - "Border Road," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 44)
      - "The Border Sector," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 45)
      - "Boutiques," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 46)
      - "The Boyles," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 47)
      - "Building an Ark," MS (Box 20, Folder 48)
      - "Burning Old Shoes," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 49)
      - "Burst Mains / Lisburn Road," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 50)
      - "By-Pass," TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 20, Folder 51)
      - "Canoeist," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 52)
      - "The Carpet Warehouse," MS (Box 20, Folder 53)
      - "Cemetery in Winter," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 54)
      - "A Ceremonial Occasion," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 20, Folder 55)
      - "Chains," MS (Box 20, Folder 56)
      - "The Charladies," MS [See Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Store of Candles, "Natural History Selection"]
      - "Charles the Wrestler," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 57)
      - "The Child," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 58)
      - "Chinese Take Away," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 59)
      - "Cholera," MS (Box 20, Folder 60)
      - "City Buildings," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 61)
      - "City and Sky," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 20, Folder 62)
      - "City Church, With Offices," TS (Box 20, Folder 63)
      - "Civilian Funerals," MS [variant title: "A Minute's Silence"] [included with A Northern Spring materials] (Box 20, Folder 64)
      - "Classroom Meditation," TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 20, Folder 65)
      - "Clay," MS (Box 20, Folder 66)
      - "The Cleaning Ladies," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 20, Folder 67)
      - "Clearances," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 68)
      - "A Conservation Poem," TS (Box 20, Folder 69)
      - "Continuities," TS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Working Days" and "The Unemployed"] (Box 20, Folder 70)
      - "The Copper Beech," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 71)
      - "Corncrake," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 20, Folder 72)
      - "Corporation Bus Ticket," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Well-Wisher"] [variant title: "The Lament of the Corporation Bus-Tickets"] (Box 20, Folder 73)
      - "The Cottage at the Wood's Edge," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 20, Folder 74)
      - "A Country Cottage: Towards Dawn," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 75)
      - "A Country Night's Entertainment," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 76)
      - "Coverage," MS [variant title: "The Second Assignment"] [included with A Northern Spring materials] (Box 20, Folder 77)
      - "Crab Apples," TS (Box 20, Folder 78)
      - "The Crocodiles at Killyhevlin," TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 20, Folder 79)
      - "Cul de Sac," MS (Box 20, Folder 80)
      - "The Cyclone," MS (Box 20, Folder 81)
      - "A Day in August," TS (Box 20, Folder 82)
      - "Dead Canals," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1b, Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "Ste-Mère-Eglise"] (Box 20, Folder 83)
      - "Defense of Poesie," TS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Derrycullen Churchyard" for MS] (Box 20, Folder 84)
      - "Derrycullen Churchyard," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 85)
      - "Desk Graffitti: A Serious Reading," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 20, Folder 86)
      - "The Devil's Advocate," MS, TS [included with A Northern Spring materials] (Box 20, Folder 87)
      - "The Disappearance of the Lough," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 88)
      - "Distances," MS [variant title: Outside the Window"] (Box 20, Folder 89)
      - "Docken In, Nettle Out," TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 20, Folder 90)
      - "The Doctor," MS [Also includes fragment entitled "The Diary"] [included with A Northern Spring materials] (Box 20, Folder 91)
      - "Donne," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 92)
      - "Doorstep," TS (Box 20, Folder 93)
      - "Drains, Near Enniskillen," TS (Box 20, Folder 94)
      - "Dustmen," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 95)
      - "Edges," TS (Box 20, Folder 96)
      - "The Eighth Day," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 97)
      - "The Eldest Son at the Cemetery Gates," TS (Box 20, Folder 98)
      - "Elegy," MS, TS [this poem is different from "Elegy" in Business as Usual] (Box 20, Folder 99)
      - "An Elegy for Patrick Kelly," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 100)
      - "11th May 1985," MS (Box 20, Folder 101)
      - "Empty Office, Lunch Hours," MS (Box 20, Folder 102)
      - "End Terrace," MS, TS (Box 20, Folder 103)
      - "Epitaph for a Parochial Worker," TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 20, Folder 104)
      - "Eustachian," MS (Box 20, Folder 105)
      - "Evasions," TS [included originally with A Northern Spring materials] (Box 20, Folder 106)
      - "The Execution of Herbaux," MS (Box 20, Folder 107)
      - "The Facts," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - "February," MS [variant title: "Sharing"] (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - "58° 32' N 8° 8' E," MS [See Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "Safe Home"]
      - "Finding Spent Cartridges," TS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Hedge-Schools"] (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - "First Girl," TS (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - "First Stone," TS (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - "First Tooth," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - "Florencecourt and the Marble Arch Caves," MS (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - "Folk Museum," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - "The Football Hooligan," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - "For M. in Delirium," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - "Foreign Games," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - "Four Chinese Take-Aways," TS (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - "Fragment," TS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Meetings"] (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - "Freddy," TS (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - "French Kissing," MS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Burning Old Shoes" and "Sensualities"]
      - "From the Kitchen Windows," MS, TS [variant title: "View from the Kitchen Windows"] (Box 21, Folder 15)
      - "Fuel," MS, TS [variant title: "Filling Station"] (Box 21, Folder 16)
      - "Gatehouse," TS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "The Places in Me"] (Box 21, Folder 17)
      - "Gates," MS, TS [variant title: "The Two Gates"] (Box 21, Folder 18)
      - "Getting to Know," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 19)
      - "Giants," TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 21, Folder 20)
      - "Giraldo's Story," MS (Box 21, Folder 21)
      - "Girl," TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 21, Folder 22)
      - "The Goalkeeper," MS [See also Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby (poetry), "The Goalkeeper"] (Box 21, Folder 23)
      - "Going to See Mary," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 21, Folder 24)
      - "Grandfather McQuillan," MS (Box 21, Folder 25)
      - "Green Bottles," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Tracks"] (Box 21, Folder 26)
      - "Haiku," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 21, Folder 27)
      - "Happy Anniversary," MS [See Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby (poetry), "One Saturday," MS]
      - "Happy Love," MS, TS [See Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "February"] (Box 21, Folder 28)
      - "Heads I Win…," MS, TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 21, Folder 29)
      - "A Healthy Parrot," MS (Box 21, Folder 30)
      - "Hedge-Schools," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Two Poems," "Finding Spent Cartridges"] (Box 21, Folder 31)
      - "Heritage," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 32)
      - "High Wind," TS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 21, Folder 33)
      - "The Home Fires," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 21, Folder 34)
      - "Hothouse," TS [variant title: "Two Visits to the Hotpress," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 35)
      - "The House By Night," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 36)
      - "The Housing Situation," TS (Box 21, Folder 37)
      - "Human Figures, With Fence and Two Stools," MS (Box 21, Folder 38)
      - "Husbandry," MS [variant title: "Indoor Plants"] (Box 21, Folder 39)
      - "I Envy You…," TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 21, Folder 40)
      - "I Witness the Revolution," MS (Box 21, Folder 41)
      - "Imaginings," TS (Box 21, Folder 42)
      - "In the Bicycle Shed," MS [See Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Chains," MS]
      - "In the Murder Triangle," TS (Box 21, Folder 43)
      - "In Time of Darkness," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 44)
      - "Inferno: A New Circle," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 45)
      - "Instructions," MS (Box 21, Folder 46)
      - "Interior Seasons," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 47)
      - "Interior Summer," TS (Box 21, Folder 48)
      - "An Introduction," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 49)
      - "Island Honeymoon," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 21, Folder 50)
      - "Islander," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 21, Folder 51)
      - "James," TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 21, Folder 52)
      - "Jaundiced Portrait of the Artist as Observer," TS [See Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "The Eldest Son at the Cemetery Gates"]
      - "Jim Lyttle's Second-Hand Bookshop," MS [See Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Donne"] (Box 21, Folder 53)
      - "Joseph of Nazareth," MS (Box 21, Folder 54)
      - "Kelly Remembers," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 21, Folder 55)
      - "Kelly's Reproach," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 21, Folder 56)
      - "Keyholders," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 57)
      - "A Kind of fury—so the Captain said…," MS [included originally with A Northern Spring materials] (Box 21, Folder 58)
      - "Labourers," TS (Box 21, Folder 59)
      - "The Lake and the Mountain," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 60)
      - "The Lapsed Catholic Attends Mass," MS (Box 21, Folder 61)
      - "Last of a Brood," TS [circa pre-1971] [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Derrycullen Churchyard" for MS] (Box 21, Folder 62)
      - "Le Jardin Du Luxembourg," MS (Box 21, Folder 63)
      - "Leaving the Hospital," MS, TS [variant title: "Your brown suitcase across my knees…"] (Box 21, Folder 64)
      - "Licking the Clitoris," MS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Burning Old Shoes" and "Sensualities"]
      - "Listener," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 65)
      - "Listening to Water," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 66)
      - "Loading and Unloading," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 21, Folder 67)
      - "Losing a Day," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 68)
      - "Love All Imagining," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 69)
      - "The Love of Helen Keller," MS, TS [variant title: "Learning About Helen Keller"] [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Tracks"] (Box 21, Folder 70)
      - "Lunchtime at the City Hall," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 21, Folder 71)
      - "M. On Night Duty," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 72)
      - "Man and Superman," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 73)
      - "Manifesto," MS (Box 21, Folder 74)
      - "A Man's Gotta Do…," MS (Box 21, Folder 75)
      - "Marble Arch Caves," TS (Box 21, Folder 76)
      - "Market Day," MS (Box 21, Folder 77)
      - "Masters," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Working Days"] [variant title: "September"] (Box 21, Folder 78)
      - "Maverick," TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Store of Candles, "Calendars"] (Box 21, Folder 79)
      - "Mechanics," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 80)
      - "Meeting the Vicar," MS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Store of Candles, "Winter Offerings"] (Box 21, Folder 81)
      - "Meetings," TS (Box 21, Folder 82)
      - "A Memory of Summer," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 83)
      - "Mews," MS (Box 21, Folder 84)
      - "Midfielder," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 85)
      - "Minutes," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 86)
      - "A Minute's Silence," MS (Box 21, Folder 87)
      - "Missing Buses," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 88)
      - "Missing Persons," MS (Box 21, Folder 89)
      - "A Missionary Calls," MS (Box 21, Folder 90)
      - "Moneyspeak," MS (Box 21, Folder 91)
      - "More Lessons of the War," TS (Box 21, Folder 92)
      - "Mortgaged," MS, TS [variant title: "Ownership"] (Box 21, Folder 93)
      - "My Mother's Asthma," MS [included originally with A Northern Spring materials] (Box 21, Folder 94)
      - "My Septic Navel," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 21, Folder 95)
      - "Near an Airport," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 96)
      - "Net Curtains," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 97)
      - "A New Neighbour," MS, TS [variant title: "Night on Black's Farm"] (Box 21, Folder 98)
      - "Nightflight," TS (Box 21, Folder 99)
      - "Nightpeace," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 100)
      - "Nineteen Ninety-Four," MS (Box 21, Folder 101)
      - "A Ninth Birthday," MS (Box 21, Folder 102)
      - "Nocturne," MS, TS [variant title: "Last Night" and "Frost in the Avenue;" note: no relation to other poems with "Nocturne" in titles] (Box 21, Folder 103)
      - "Nocturnes: 1. Traffic Lights at Night," MS, TS [variant title: "Lyric"] (Box 21, Folder 104)
      - "November," MS [included originally with A Northern Spring materials] (Box 21, Folder 105)
      - "Off-Camera," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 106)
      - "Oil," MS, TS [variant title: "Egypt"] (Box 21, Folder 107)
      - "The Old Fan's Lament," TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Store of Candles, "Islands"] (Box 21, Folder 108)
      - "An Old Map," MS, TS (Box 21, Folder 109)
      - "Once a Month," MS, TS [variant title: "Seen from the Window"] [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Store of Candles, "Fanfares"] (Box 21, Folder 110)
      - "Open Day at the Base," MS [included originally with A Northern Spring materials] (Box 21, Folder 111)
      - "Orangeberry," MS (Box 21, Folder 112)
      - "Orlando," MS (Box 21, Folder 113)
      - "A.N. Other," MS (Box 21, Folder 114)
      - "Out of the Game for Long Periods," MS (Box 21, Folder 115)
      - "Out of the Woods," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 21, Folder 116)
      - "A Pair of Shorts," TS [includes "The All-Time Greats," MS, TS; "Out of the Game for Long Periods, TS] (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - "Parks and Cemeteries," MS (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - "The Passengers," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - "Patrick," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - "Pavements," TS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "City Building"] (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - "The Peace Proposals," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - "Perspective on Grief," MS (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - "The Philosopher," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - "Pine Coffins," [included originally with A Northern Spring materials] (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - "The Places in Me," TS (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - "Poem," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - "Poem for a Daughter," TS (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - "A Poem for Prize-Giving," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - "Poetry and Water," MS (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - "The Playing Fields of America," MS [See Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "Some of Us Stayed Forever"]
      - "Positive," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - "Post Mortem," [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Husbandry"] (Box 22, Folder 16)
      - "Premarital Rite, Castle Junction," MS, TS [variant titles: "Roundabout" and "Getting Married"] (Box 22, Folder 17)
      - "Preparing for Flight," TS (Box 22, Folder 18)
      - "Private Eye," TS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "The Eldest Son at the Cemetery Gates"] (Box 22, Folder 19)
      - "Promises," MS [variant title: "Meetings" (different from other poem entitled "Meetings")] (Box 22, Folder 20)
      - "Purgatorio," MS, TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 22, Folder 21)
      - "Purled," MS (Box 22, Folder 22)
      - "The Rabbits," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 23)
      - "Regional," TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (unpublished poetry collections), untitled pamphlet (pre-1971)] (Box 22, Folder 24)
      - "Remains," MS [variant title: "Women at the City Morgue"] [included originally with A Northern Spring materials] (Box 22, Folder 25)
      - "Remembering Courtship," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 26)
      - "Rendezvous," MS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "The Carpet Warehouse"]
      - "Restocking the Supermarket," MS [variant title: "The Siege"] (Box 22, Folder 27)
      - "Rheumatism," MS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Well-Wisher"] (Box 22, Folder 28)
      - "Roger Fenton in the Crimea," MS (Box 22, Folder 29)
      - "Rommel Prepares," MS, TS [variant titles: "Award for Progress," and "The Atlantic Wall"] [included originally with A Northern Spring materials] (Box 22, Folder 30)
      - "Rush-Hour," MS, TS [variant title: "Morning Rush-Hour"] (Box 22, Folder 31)
      - "The Safety-Valve Sequence," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 22, Folder 32)
      - "Saffron Observation," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 22, Folder 33)
      - "St. Patrick's Well," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 34)
      - "Sale or Return," MS (Box 22, Folder 35)
      - "Sarajevo," MS (Box 22, Folder 36)
      - "Scholarship to the Seminary," TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 22, Folder 37)
      - "The Search," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 38)
      - "The Secret Lives of the Saints," MS (Box 22, Folder 39)
      - "Security Man: City Restaurant," MS, TS [variant title: "The Security Man"] (Box 22, Folder 40)
      - "Sensualities," TS (Box 22, Folder 41)
      - "Shoreline," MS (Box 22, Folder 42)
      - "Sightings," MS, TS [variant title: "Her Recent Public Appearances"] (Box 22, Folder 43)
      - "Silver and Green," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 44)
      - "Sleeping Alone," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 45)
      - "The Sleepwalker," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 46)
      - "Sloes," TS (Box 22, Folder 47)
      - "Smells of the home bakery…," MS (Box 22, Folder 48)
      - "Snow muffled at the core of night…," MS (Box 22, Folder 49)
      - "Somme Veterans," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 50)
      - "Sources," TS (Box 22, Folder 51)
      - "Spoilt Child," TS (Box 22, Folder 52)
      - "Sports Pages," MS (Box 22, Folder 53)
      - "Spring Flooding," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 54)
      - "Spring in the Air," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 55)
      - "Squatters, July 1969" TS (Box 22, Folder 56)
      - "Still Life," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 57)
      - "Stock-Car," TS [circa pre-1971] [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Derrycullen Churchyard"] (Box 22, Folder 58)
      - "Stones," TS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Two Poems," "Finding Spent Cartridges"] (Box 22, Folder 59)
      - "A Sunday Afternoon in Barnett's Park," MS (Box 22, Folder 60)
      - "Sunday Evening," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 22, Folder 61)
      - "Teasing the Defense," MS (Box 22, Folder 62)
      - "Terrace House, With Sylph," TS (Box 22, Folder 63)
      - "These Are the Generals," MS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "Some of Us Stayed Forever"] (Box 22, Folder 64)
      - "The Third Day Out," TS [See also Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Northern Spring, "A Northern Spring" sequence] (Box 22, Folder 65)
      - "Time Traveller," MS (Box 22, Folder 66)
      - "The Tongue," MS (Box 22, Folder 67)
      - "Tracks," TS [includes: "1. Green Bottles," "2. Learning About Helen Keller," "3. Tracks"] (Box 22, Folder 68)
      - "Trainees," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 69)
      - "The Tramp," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 70)
      - "Two Poems," TS [includes: "Hedge Schools" and "Stones"] [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Stones"] (Box 22, Folder 71)
      - "Unapproved Route," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 72)
      - "The Unemployed," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 22, Folder 73)
      - "Unionist Party Headquarters," TS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "The Eldest Son at the Cemetery Gates"] (Box 22, Folder 74)
      - "Used Cars," TS (Box 22, Folder 75)
      - "A View of History," MS [included originally with A Northern Spring materials] (Box 22, Folder 76)
      - "A Vision," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 22, Folder 77)
      - "A Visit to the Gatehouse," MS, TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 22, Folder 78)
      - "Visiting Time," TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 22, Folder 79)
      - "Volcanic Island," MS (Box 22, Folder 80)
      - "Waiting for the Bride," TS (Box 22, Folder 81)
      - "Waiting for a Connection," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 82)
      - "Waiting for M.," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 22, Folder 83)
      - "Walking Home at Night," MS, TS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Losing a Day"] (Box 22, Folder 84)
      - "Walkers Observed," MS [See Subseries 3.1b: Poetry by Ormsby (collected), A Store of Candles, "Caves"]
      - "Wanderlust," TS (Box 22, Folder 85)
      - "War Games," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 22, Folder 86)
      - "War Memorial I," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 22, Folder 87)
      - "Waste Ground Near a Bridge," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 88)
      - "Water," TS [variant title: "Poetry and Water"] (Box 22, Folder 89)
      - "Wedding Photograph," TS [See Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "James;" circa pre-1971]